# PRIYANKA DHANABAL

# Junior Full Stack Developer

**GitHub**: https://github.com/Priyanka-Dhanabal

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/priyanka-dhanabal/

Email ID: priyanka.dhanabal96@gmail.com

Mobile: +49(0) 1777988482 Location: Crailsheim, Germany



### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

Junior Software Developer, currently studying for a Diploma in Full-stack Software Development from the Code Institute. Proficient in Front-end and Back-end technologies. I have 3 years of experience working as a Senior Service Engineer. I am a valuable team player with strong communication skills and effective problem-solving ability. I am eager to gain entry into the tech industry as a software developer and be part of an exciting team where I can grow and contribute.

#### **EDUCATION**

Feb 2024 – Present **Diploma in Full Stack Software Development** 

Student at Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland – (Credit Rated by University of West of Scotland).

Aug 2014 – Jun 2018 Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical and Electronics

CMR Institute of Technology, Bangalore, India.

# **SKILLS**

FRONTEND DEVELOPMENT | HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap
BACKEND DEVELOPMENT | Python
DATABASES | MySQL

VERSION CONTROL | Git, GitHub, Heroku

MISCELLANEOUS | PowerShell, C/C++, VMware vSphere, Windows and Linux OS

**SOFT SKILLS** | Team player, Deliver results, Eager to learn, Effective Verbal and Written Communication

LINGUISTICS | Tamil(Native), English(Native), Hindi(Advanced), German(Beginner)

## **PROJECTS**

Portfolio Project - RideAlong | A Responsive website, Technologies used | HTML5, CSS3 GitHub - https://github.com/Priyanka-Dhanabal/RideAlong

Portfolio Project - MarvelMania | A responsive and interactive quiz Marvel-themed website Technologies used | HTML5, CSS3, Vanilla JavaScript GitHub - https://github.com/Priyanka-Dhanabal/MarvelManiaQuiz\_PP2

Portfolio Project - Cut-2-Chase | A terminal-based project. A Game where players guess a letter from a word chosen by a computer at random.

Technologies used | Python

GitHub - https://github.com/Priyanka-Dhanabal/cut-2-chase-pp3

Bachelor's Project | EMS for Reliance Industries Limited at Jamnagar by ABB, India

- Analyzing and understanding load-shedding operations used by ABB
- Testing of Electrical network (CT/PT prototype and transducer)
- Hand Soldering, wiring, and labeling for electrical apparatus in Panels.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Feb 2020 – Nov 2021

Senior Service Engineer Microland, Bangalore, India

- Expertise in Creating virtual machines, installing operating systems (Windows and Linux), installing tools, and configuring these VMs based on customer requirements.
- Managing ESXi hosts from the Virtual center and through UCSM. Monitoring and administrating servers through VMware Vrealize operations and SCOM.
- Creating and Administrating user and computer accounts in Active Directory and Cloud IAM portal. Managing DNS, and IP entries in software IPAM.
- Actively taking part in Incident calls as an On-call Engineer.

Feb 2019 - Jan 2020

Service Engineer Microland, Bangalore, India

- Monitoring, and resolving L1 alerts and requests triggered on ServiceNow, SCOM, JIRA, and via mailbox.
- Provisioning new client ID accounts applying necessary initial settings, and troubleshooting issues related to accounts login into the application.
- Perform various application testing post RTR (Change request) as per SOP and escalate to QA and DEV team in case of any abnormalities.
- Hosting Incident Calls and inviting on-call engineers according to the issue. Send periodic communication reports.

Priyanka Dhanabal Place: Crailsheim